"Who used up my toothpaste"
“那是谁 用掉了 我的牙膏”
"Who walked off with my shoes and coat"
“我的鞋 和外套 是谁穿走了”
"Who stayed at my house and took a shower"
“那是谁 在我家 大方洗澡”
"In the mirror he and I share the same appearance"
“镜子前 他和我 一样的外表”
"Who moved into my head"
“谁搬进 我的大脑”
"Who controlled my hands and feet"
“谁控制 我的手脚”
"Is my DNA rebelling against me"
“是DNA 唱我反调”
"Or it is me that dare not to determine my own ate"
“还是我 的命运 不敢自编自导”
"Wanna shout,then shout"
“想要叫 那就叫”
"Wanna shake,then shake,wanna jump,then jump"
“想甩就甩跳就跳”
"Jump higher,not with your waist"
“跳更高 别靠腰”
"But with the fire in your heart"
“要靠心脏的火药”
"What do you want?"
“要不要 难道要”
"You want someone else to decide it for you?"
“别人帮你决定好”
"How about right now"
“好不好 就现在”
"You steal back your own heartbeat"
“抢回自己的心跳”
"Your own heartbeat"
“自己的心跳”
"Who always sounds so defeated"
“那是谁 总是说 有够衰小”
"Who only prays and brags"
“那是谁 只祷告 只想打嘴炮”
"Who is arrested"
“那是谁 被通缉 正在逃跑”
"On a charge of kidnapping his own smile"
“罪名是 绑架了  自己的微笑”
"Who moved into my head"
“谁搬进 我的大脑”
"Who controlled my hands and feet"
“谁控制 我的手脚”
"Is my DNA rebelling against me"
“是DNA 唱我反调”
"Or it is me that dare not to determine my own fate"
“还是我 的命运 不敢自编自导”
"Wanna yell,then yell"
“想要叫 那就叫”
"Wanna shake,then shake,jump and jump"
“想甩就甩跳就跳”
"Jump higher,not with your waist"
“跳更高 别靠腰”
"But with the fire in your heart"
“要靠心脏的火药”
"What do you want?"
“要不要 难道要”
"You want someone else to decide for you?"
“别人帮你决定好”
"How about right now"
“好不好 就现在”
"You steal back your own heartbeat"
“抢回自己的心跳”
"Wanna yell,then yell"
“想要叫 那就叫”
"Wanna shake,then shake,jump and jump"
“想甩就甩跳就跳”
"Jump higher,not with your waist"
“跳更高 别靠腰”
"but with the fire in your heart"
“要靠心脏的火药”
"What do you want?"
“要不要 难道要”
"You want someone else to decide for you?"
“别人帮你决定好”
"How about right now"
“好不好 就现在”
You steal back your own heartbeat
抢回自己的心跳
"Thump jump sprint run"
“心跳 跳跃 狂奔 奔跑”
"Shake shake shake shake"
“摇咧摇咧摇咧摇”
"A heart thumping crazily"
“一颗心噗通噗通的狂跳”
"Leaving all troubles behind"
“一瞬间烦恼烦恼烦恼全忘掉”
"I throw away the earth"
“我甩掉地球 地球甩掉”
"Jump higher and higher"
“只要越跳越高”
"Throw away your watch,throw off your coat"
“丢掉手表 丢外套”
"Throw away your backpack£¬ and throw off your chatter"
“丢掉背包 再丢唠叨”
"Throw away your TV,throw out your computer"
“丢掉电视 丢电脑”
"Throw away your brain,throw off your troubles"
“丢掉大脑 再丢烦恼”
"No matter what you do"
“冲啥大 冲啥小”
"There will always be someone against you"
“冲啥都有人唱反调”
"Hate too much,love so little"
“恨得多 爱得少”
"Jump high and crazy as possible"
“只想越跳越疯 越跳越高”
"Throw away the earth"
“把地球甩掉”
"A heart thumping crazily"
“一颗心噗通噗通的狂跳”
"Leaving all troubles behind"
“一瞬间烦恼烦恼烦恼全忘掉”
"I will never and never"
“我再也不要 再也不要”
"Make myself feel wronged for another second"
“委屈自己一秒”
"A heart thumping crazily"
“一颗心噗通噗通的狂跳”
"Leaving all troubles behind"
“一瞬间烦恼烦恼烦恼全忘掉”
"I throw away the earth"
“我甩掉地球 地球甩掉”
"Jump higher and higher"
“只要越跳越高”
Come on
来吧
"Throw away your watch,throw off your coat"
“丢掉手表 丢外套”
"Throw away your backpack£¬ and throw off your chatter"
“丢掉背包 再丢唠叨”
"Throw away your TV,throw out your computer"
“丢掉电视 丢电脑”
"Throw away your brain,throw off your troubles"
“丢掉大脑 再丢烦恼”
"Great ambitions,little courage"
“野心大 胆子小”
"Still need a dance instructor?"
“跳舞还要靠别人教”
"Hate too much,love so little"
“恨得多 爱得少”
"Jump high and crazy as possible"
“只想越跳越疯 越跳越高”
"Throw away the earth"
“把地球甩掉”
"A heart thumping crazily"
“一颗心噗通噗通的狂跳”
"Leaving all troubles behind"
“一瞬间烦恼烦恼烦恼全忘掉”
"I will never and never"
“我再也不要 再也不要”
"Make myself feel wronged for another second"
“委屈自己一秒”
"A heart thumping crazily"
“一颗心噗通噗通的狂跳”
"Leaving all troubles behind"
“一瞬间烦恼烦恼烦恼全忘掉”
"I throw away the earth"
“甩掉地球 地球甩掉”
"Jump higher and higher"
“只要越跳越高”
Come on
来吧
"A heart thumping crazily"
“一颗心噗通噗通的狂跳”
"Leaving all troubles behind"
“一瞬间烦恼烦恼烦恼全忘掉”
"I will never and never"
“我再也不要 再也不要”
"make myself feel wronged for another second"
“委屈自己一秒”
"A heart thumping crazily"
“一颗心噗通噗通的狂跳”
"Leaving all troubles behind"
“一瞬间烦恼烦恼烦恼全忘掉”
"I throw away the earth"
“我甩掉地球 地球甩掉”
"Jump higher and higher"
“只要越跳越高”
Come on
来吧
Jump
跳
"I've walked through restless days"
“我 走过动荡日子”
"Chased dreams audaciously"
“追过梦的放肆”
"Passed through lives and deaths"
“穿过多少生死”
"Yet I pretended to be calm"
“却 假装若无其事”
"Passing through half of the city"
“穿过半个城市”
"Just to get a glimpse of you"
“只想看你样子”
"This moment,the most important thing"
“这一刻 最重要的事”
"Is you,my most trivial matter"
“是属于你 最小的事”
"The world is full of chaos and noises"
“世界纷纷扰扰喧宣闹闹”
"What is the truth"
“什么是真实”
"I don't mind stumbling or being a smiling fool for you"
“为你跌跌撞撞傻傻笑笑”
"I will buy you a cup ofjuice"
“买一杯果汁”
"Even if I have to lead an ordinary and busy life"
“就算庸庸碌碌匆匆忙忙”
"All these years"
“活过一辈子”
"Every second,minute,day and year"
“也要分分秒秒年年日日”
"I will protect you with all might even at the most trivial matter"
“全心守护你 最小的事”
"You smile like a child"
“你 笑得像个孩子”
"And turn every ordinary trivial thing"
“每个平凡小事”
"Into eternal legend"
“变成永恒故事”
"The world is full of chaos and noises"
“世界纷纷扰扰喧宣闹闹”
"What is the truth"
“什么是真实”
"I don't mind stumbling or being a smiling fool for you"
“为你跌跌撞撞傻傻笑笑”
"I will buy you a cup ofjuice"
“买一杯果汁”
"Even if I have to lead an ordinary and busy life"
“算庸庸碌碌匆匆忙忙”
"All these years"
“活过一辈子”
"Every second,minute,day and year"
“也要分分秒秒年年日日”
"I will protect you with all might"
“全心守护你”
"Even at the most trivial matter"
“最小的事”
"The most important matter"
“最重要的事”
Welcome,welcome
欢迎光临
Shing,quickly,we have lots of customers
兴仔 弄那么半天 那么多客人
Whatever you do
你想怎么样啊
hurry up
手脚俐落一点
Give me 2 rice noodles
弄两个河粉 两个河粉
The curry here is excellent
这里的咖哩鱼蛋超诺
I know,I told you so
我知道 我跟你讲的啊
Hey,table for 2
老板老板 我们两位 两位
Who do you think you are? Get in line!
两位也要排队啊 你以为你是谁啊
Shing!
兴仔
Well,maybe we can come visit next time
那怎么办 算了 那下次吃啦
Yeah,so many people,maybe next time...
先走吧
Wow,MAYDAY's autograph CD
哇 五月天亲笔签名CD耶
- Excellent! Excellent! - Like it?
太好了 太好了       喜欢吗
Of course!
当然
Did you have the secret recipe?
神秘鱼蛋学会了没
Fatty said it is a secret family recipe
肥叔说这是他的传家宝
You are the only one that will know that secret
大概他只会传给你 不会传给我
Well... I am not interested in that at all
不会吧 我没有想做鱼蛋耶
Dad,Dad
爸爸爸爸
What's up,honey?
干嘛啊 乐乐
Look,Dad
爸爸爸爸 你看你看
Here is the gift from Shing-
这是兴仔哥哥送给我的
MAYDAY's autograph CD!
五月天亲笔签名CD
What is this?
什么呀 这是
He's really nice to me
他对我很好耶
Please give him that recipe
你就教他做那个神秘鱼蛋吧
Over my dead body!
他要洗多几年底裤再说吧
You are my sweet heart
你是爸爸的乖乖女
You should be the one to have it
爸爸神秘鱼蛋当然交给你啦
No,Dad
不要不要啦 爹地
I don't want to run this restaurant
我以后长大我不要做鱼蛋
I want to be a star,and even sing with MAYDAY
我要当明星 跟五月天同台唱歌
"Love-i-n-g,Happy-i-n-g"
“恋爱ing 快乐ing”
"Now,what I feel is like riding on..."
“心情就像是 坐上…”
O.K.,Karen,I know,I know
好好好 我知道了Karen
I will get you the tickets
买好了 票买好了 带你去
Hey,where is our order?
老板 我们的面怎么还没到啊
O.K.,2 people at table 3
好好 两位三号桌
Dad
爸爸
You are back
回来啦 大小姐 乖啦
Get change,and wash your hands
去换换衣服 换衣服 把书包放下
It's dinner time
洗手洗手吃东西啊 吃饭了
O.K. O.K.
好了好了好了 来来来放点葱来
take that and wash this
乖啦去去去把书包放下放下
No time for games?
哎呀 不玩大灰狼喜羊羊啊
Put down your book bag and let's eat
把书包放下吃饭 来了来了来了
What are you gonna do? You big bad wolf
怎么样啊 大灰狼
Dad,I want to go to MAYDAY's concert
爸爸 我要去看五月天演唱会
MAYDAY? Are you kidding me?
五月天啊 哎呀 宝贝呀 你看看
It is October already...
现在都十月了 还五月天
MAYDAY will have a concert in Shanghai
五月天要在上海唱四面台
It will be brilliant
很厉害的
Hua,Mi,Bobo will all be there,I want to go,too
小华 阿咪 波波都要去 我也要去嘛
Shanghai? You kids?
哎呀 上海啊 危险啊
No! Too dangerous!
你们几个小朋友 不行
Please,please,please!
你就让我去吧
Be a good girl,O.K.?
听话听话
No£¬
不行
I don't care who they are
我不理你五月六月七月八月九月天都好
No means no,I mean it!
不行就是不行 听话
Morning
早安 乐乐
See,what we are having for today
你看今天午饭有个大鸡腿啊
No way,are you holding a hunger strike?
不会吧 绝食抗议啊
Dear¡­
亲爱的
do you like my lipstick?
你看我今天涂的唇膏颜色好不好看
They are having a big sale around Time Square
亲爱的 时代广场最近在打折
How about we go together after work?
下班我们一起去好不好
Hey,are you listening to me?
你这个人怎么这样子
Karen,I am really busy
Karen 我真的很忙
Oh,rats
小气鬼
Shing,I want to see your boss
兴仔 叫你们老板出来
- I am here. - What do you want?
老板在这       干嘛
Honey,is everything alright?
怎么啦 乐乐 不舒服啊
Fatty,I want to talk to you
肥仔 我要跟你谈判
- Why so serious? - Get in
哇 谈判       进来
Friend of yours?
谁啊 朋友啊
Sit
坐下
This is my lawyer
这是我的法律顾问
I have being helping out around this place since I was 10
我从三年级起就在家里帮忙
365 days per year,1095 in total
一年365天 三年就是1，095天
5 hours per day,5475 in total
每天工作5小时 就是5，475小时
Since you're still my Dad
念在我们父女一场
I will charge you $5 per hour
我就算你5块钱1小时
That will be $27375 in total
你一共欠我27，375元
Give me my money back,fatso
肥仔 给钱
What do you want the money for?
两万多 要那么多钱
Health insurance for your old man?
帮爸爸买养老保险
Of course not!
才不是呢
Those are for the MAYDAY concert
我要用我自己的钱去看演唱会
Not again!
演唱会 我说来说去你都不明白
I told you money was not the issue here
爸爸说不是钱的问题
Are you going to pay me or not?
你给不给
I will sue you against the children labor law
你不给我告你虐待童工
Oh,that sounds bad
虐待童工
Who are you anyway?
你是哪位 虐待童工啊
None of my business
不关我的事
She offers me a free meal
是她让我跟你聊天
As long as I am here,talking to you
然后请我吃咖哩鱼蛋嘛
A free meal?
请你吃咖哩鱼蛋
Are you Friggen kidding me?
我厕所有一桶你要不要
You dipshit!
你吃屎啦
What's that for?
干什么啊 这是
Baby girl
小宝贝
Dad made your favorite meal
你看爸爸弄了你最喜欢吃的比鼻鸭
Dad just worry about you
你长得那么漂亮
It is really dangerous for you to travel alone
爸爸怕你一个人出去
It's really not safe out there
去这么远
Do you hear me?
你听到没有
Dad will watch the concert DVD with you
爸爸拿了光盆一起看好不好
It's very similar anyway
跟演唱会的感觉是一模一样啊
You can sing and dance with them as well
你可以唱 躺着看也行坐着看也行
Stay here with Dad?
跟爸爸一起看啊
Baby girl?
宝贝啊
What,Hun?
干嘛 宝贝
Dad,see this?
爸爸 你看
I can attack bad guys with this. Come in
如果我去上海遇到坏人
I can attack bad guys with this.
我可以用这个攻击他
Come on
进来
Come
来
Sit,Dad
爸爸 坐
What is the solution here?
有什么好建议
Dad,see this?
爸爸 我告诉你
This is the best one
我有一样最最厉害的武器
Personal security spray
看 这是防狼喷雾剂
And,the legendary ShaoLin Blade
这就是传说中的少林刀
It is a very powerful weapon
可是很厉害的
See,how sharp it is
你就可以被 大卸八块
See this?
你看这个
The cops will come and rescue me£¬
就会有警察来救我
Don't you worry about me
你不用担心我的安危
Dad,see this bow and arrow?
爸爸 你看这个弓箭
It is the most powerful one
这是最厉害的 百发百中
You can't miss the target at all
如果我射你一箭
Baby girl£¬
宝宝
These are useless
这个是不行的
You know why?
知道吗
These are just toys
这个完全没有杀伤力
Listen to me,Shanghai is too far away
还有 听爸爸话
How can you travel to such a far away place?
那是那么远 那么小小朋友怎么可以呢
Can you stop all of this?
听话了好不好
Dad,please?
爸爸你让我去嘛
Listen to me just once
你听话好不好啊
Please stop
怎么说都不听呢
Dad
爸爸
When Mom died£¬
妈妈去世的时候
You promised to take good care of me
你答应过她会好好照顾我的
But¡­
可是你
Honey
乖啦 不要哭啊
Please do not cry
爸爸委屈你了吗
I am sorry about the decision
爸爸委屈你了啊
Sorry
不要这样
Baby girl
乖宝宝
I am really sorry
爸爸委屈你了
But,you have to listen to me
但你要听话 你听爸爸话
If Mom were here
爸爸知道如果妈妈在的时候
She would take you there
就妈妈带你去嘛
So,please be a good girl,O.K.?
乖 好吗
Anybody here?
有没有人啊
I want that...
老板 我想要那个 那个 那个
What are you talking about?
哪个歌星啊
Something about losing yourself
那个那个家里什么丢掉那个
"Losing¡­"
“丢…丢…”
"Throw away your computer£¬ throw away your backpack"
“丢电脑 丢背包”
"What's that,what's that"
“冲啥大 冲啥小”
- "That's it,that's it" - It's MAYDAY's song
“那个小 那个小”      是五月天五月天
Yeah,that is right,I am looking for that
啊 五月天 五月天有没有
At the back
后面后面
We will help you out
我帮你 我帮你
Where?
哪里 老板 哪里有
To your left
左边左边
Left?
左
This is not what I'm looking for
不是啦！我要那个
I want their tickets to the concert
那个演场会那个门票那个
You know? The tickets?
那个演唱会那个
We don't sell concert tickets
这里不卖票啊 大哥
What? Are you kidding me?
这里不卖票 那么多东西不卖票
We only sell CDs
卖CD而已啊
Anyway,where can I find the tickets?
卖CD 哪里卖票
On the internet
网路啊
What?
往哪条路
Do you have a computer?
电脑里的网路
Computer?
电脑
No
没有
Never mind,I will help you get one
帮你找 帮你找
Thanks
谢谢
- I really appreciate it - MAYDAY
可以快一点吗       五月天
All sold out
卖完
How come?
卖完再做嘛
SOLD OUT
卖完了啊 没得做了啊
Why is that?
我那鱼丸卖完 做了才好吃
Do you think they will sell more tickets?
再做一个好不好
How should I know?
票又不是我做的 神经
Oh,my daughter will kill me¡­
你不要说我神经 我就快神…
Anyhow,all sold out
没有没有 卖完了 卖完了
Can you help me out?
求求你帮我想个办法好不好
I'm out,and this is dead anyway
卖完了 不是我做的啊
Please help me out
你那么多这个东西
Please¡­
那个那个
Oh! I'm sorry
唉呀 不好意思
I told you I am out,so get out
砸店啦 神经病啦 走啦
What should I do?
走哪里去
I will go now
师父 先走
Hey,Shing
喂喂喂喂喂 兴仔
Sir?
师父
Do you know where to get the tickets?
你说还有票吗
What tickets?
票 什么票
Not the train tickets,of course
火车票我知道去火车站买
I mean MAYDAY concert tickets
我说五月天演唱会的门票
I've tried everywhere
今天跑了腿都酸了
Nuts!
神经
Karen,I'm off
Karen 我收工了
And I want to tell you something
我想跟你说
Can we reschedule the MAYDAY concert?
我们过两天五月天演唱会可以改期去吗
What? Why?
什么 为什么
I lost the tickets
是 我把票给弄丢了
Are you kidding me?
弄丢了 有没有搞错啊
Have you looked everywhere?
弄丢了 你给我好好找找
Listen to me
你听我
I don't really care
说弄丢就弄丢
You promised me
你说要带我去看的就一定要带我去看的
How can you be so untrustful?
你这个人怎么做事都不讲…
Go to hell
你吃屎吧你
Sir.
师父
See this?
你给我看清楚
Clean this part
血要放干净
All needs to be fresh
新鲜的鱼 肉很重要
Cut here
顺着鱼筋方向去刮肉
Use this part of the knife
用刀锋的后端
If you did it wrong
如果把筋刮断 混到鱼浆里
It would be all messed up
整个的味道就完蛋了
50% of this
五分刀锋
20% of that
两分刀背
And 30% of those
三分手打
Remember
记得啊
All the same direction
要顺着同一个方向搅拌
So it will get sticky
才会有黏性
And...
还有
Do you know why mine is better?
我们的鱼蛋为什么那么爽口
Because of this¡­
因为我加了
Tendons
马蹄
O.K.
鱼蛋
You know the basics now
你基本上掌握了
I am going to tell you the recipe for my special curry
我现在告诉你做咖里
Here are all the ingredients for making the curry
这里都是做咖哩的配料
However,this is not the point
但是重点不在这里
Look at yourself
你炒的像糨糊一样
Come on
炒起来 炒起来
See? You have to make it with love
炒菜要跟做人一样
Can you feel love here?
你知道什么叫感情吗
Lele is back
乐乐回来啦
You are off
乐乐放学啦
How are you feeling today?
今天有点不开心哪
"Staying up with you"
“陪你熬夜”
"Till I'm completely sick is fine"
“聊天到爆肝也没关系”
"Going shopping with you"
“陪你逛街”
"Till I become flat-footed is fine"
“逛成扁平足也没关系”
"Thank you so much"
“超感谢你”
"For bringing me to life,in awe of you"
“让我重生 整个O - R - Z”
"To rediscover the meaning of"
“让我重新认识”
"L-O-V-E"
“L-O-V-E”
"Love-ing,happy-ing"
“恋爱ing 快乐ing”
"Now what I feel"
“心情就像是”
"Is like a ride on a jet"
“坐上 一台喷射机”
"Love-ing,change-ing"
“恋爱ing 改变ing”
"We change the dusk and the dawn"
“改变了黄昏 黎明”
"With you,my heart thumps unbearably hard"
“有你都心跳到不行”
"You are like air"
“你是空气”
"Your smell is even better than air"
“但是好闻胜过了空气”
"You are like sunshine"
“你是阳光”
"Shedding light on the midnight"
“但是却能照进半夜里”
"We live by water"
“水能载舟”
"Cook congee with water to sustain our life"
“也能煮粥 喂饱了生命”
"You are like vitamin. L-O-V-E"
“你就是维他命  L - O - V - E”
"Love-ing,happy-ing"
“恋爱ing 快乐ing”
"Now what I feel"
“心情就像是”
"Is like a ride on a jet"
“坐上 一台喷射机”
"Love-ing,change-ing"
“恋爱ing 改变ing”
"We change the dusk and the dawn"
“改变了黄昏 黎明”
"With you,my heart thumps unbearably hard"
“有你都心跳到不行”
"No matter what time what date"
“未来某年某月 某分某秒”
"What I feel for you remains unchangeable"
“某日某时 某人某地 某种永远的心情”
"Would never be forgotten. L-O-V-E"
“不会忘记此刻  L - O - V - E”
"L-O-V-E,L-O-V-E"
“L-O-V-E，L-O-V-E”
"L-OVE"
“L-OVE”
Give yourself a big applause
给自己掌声鼓励
Love you all
我爱你们
"Love-ing,happy-ing"
“恋爱ing 快乐ing”
"Now what I feel"
“心情就像是”
"Is like a ride on a jet"
“坐上 一台喷射机”
"Love-ing,change-ing"
“恋爱ing 改变ing”
"We change the dusk and the dawn"
“改变了黄昏 黎明”
"With you,my heart thumps unbearably hard"
“有你都心跳到不行”
"Dusk and dawn"
“黄昏 黎明”
"All in love-ing"
“整个都恋爱ing”
"Crying in the crowd"
“人群中 哭着”
"You just want to become invisible"
“你只想变成透明的颜色”
"No dream,ach,or broken heart"
“你再也不会梦 或痛 或心动了”
"You've decided"
“你已经决定了”
"You quietly endure"
“你 静静 忍着”
"Tightly grasping yesterday in your fist"
“紧紧把昨天在拳心握着”
"The sweeter the memories are,the more they hurt"
“而回忆越是甜 就是越伤人了”
"Leave all the profound cuts"
“越是在 手心留下”
"In your palm"
“密密麻麻 深深浅浅的刀割”
"You're not truly happy"
“你不是真正的快乐”
"Your smile is just a disguise you wear"
“你的笑只是你穿的保护色”
"You've decided not to hate"
“你决定不恨了”
"Not to love"
“也决定不爱了”
"You lock up your soul forever"
“把你的灵魂 关在永远锁上的躯壳”
"You're not truly happy"
“你不是真正的快乐”
"Your wounds are unwilling to be completely healed"
“你的伤从不肯完全的愈合”
"I stand beside you"
“我站在你左侧”
"But it's like we're separated by a galaxy"
“却像隔着银河”
"If all of these were ture"
“难道就真的”
"Would you tightly hold your remorse"
“抱着遗憾一直到老了”
"Until the day you are too old to regret"
“然后才后悔着”
"You're not truly happy"
“你不是真正的快乐”
"Your smile is just a disguise you wear"
“你的笑只是你穿的保护色”
"You've decided not to hate"
“你决定不恨了”
"Not to love"
“也决定不爱了”
"You lock up your soul forever"
“把你的灵魂 关在永远锁上的躯壳”
"You're not truly happy"
“你不是真正的快乐”
"Your wounds are unwilling to be completely healed"
“你的伤从不肯完全的愈合”
"I stand beside you"
“我站在你左侧”
"But it's like we're separated by a galaxy"
“却像隔着银河”
"If all of these were ture"
“难道就真的”
"Would you tightly hold your remorse"
“抱着遗憾一直到老了”
"You deserve to be happy"
“你值得真正的快乐”
"You should pull off that disguise you wear"
“你应该脱下你穿的保护色”
"Why do you have to be punished"
“为什么失去了”
"After all the lost?"
“还要被惩罚呢”
"Can you let your agony end at this moment?"
“能不能就让 悲伤全部结束在此刻”
"Start to relive again!"
“重新开始活着”
"I'm most afraid of a sudden stillness"
“最怕 空气突然安静”
"I am most afraid of friends' concern"
“最怕 朋友突然的关心”
"I'm most afraid of memories"
“最怕回忆”
"Suddenly engulfing me in sorrows that won't subside"
“突然翻滚绞痛着不平息”
"I'm most afraid of suddenly"
“最怕突然”
"Hearing news about you"
“听到你的消息”
"If nostalgia had a sound"
“想念如果会有声音”
"I'd rather it not be mournful weeping"
“不愿那是悲伤的哭泣”
"These days at last I belong fully to myself"
“事到如今 终于让自己属于我自己”
"With my tears to remind me"
“只剩眼泪”
"How I've fooled myself"
“还骗不过自己”
"Suddenly missing you"
“突然好想你”
"Where could you be"
“你会在哪里”
"Are you doing well or not"
“过得快乐或委屈”
"Suddenly missing you"
“突然好想你”
"A sudden sharp memory"
“突然锋利的回忆”
"A sudden indistinct vision"
“突然模糊的眼睛”
"I'm most afraid of a sudden stillness"
“最怕 空气突然安静”
"I am most afraid of friends' concern"
“最怕 朋友突然的关心”
"I'm most afraid of memories"
“最怕回忆”
"Suddenly engulfing me in sorrows that won't subside"
“突然翻滚绞痛着不平息”
"I'm most afraid of suddenly"
“最怕突然”
"Hearing news about you"
“听到你的消息”
"I'm most afraid that in this life"
“最怕此生”
"Which I've already determined to live without you"
“已经决心自己过没有你”
"I'll suddenly"
“却又突然”
"Hearing news about you"
“听到你的消息”
Hey
喂
Hey,Wen
喂 小雯
What's up?
嗯 怎么了啊
Nothing
没什么啊
Just want to say...
我只是想知道
Hi
你好不好
I...
我…
Richie,stop calling me
小齐你以后
I'm fine,and we're over
不要再打来了 我现在很好
Taxi,Taxi
有车了 有车了
Bro. take it or not?
大哥 载不载啊
- Oh,rats - It's you!
带衰       都你啦
Hey,where you going?
小姐去哪里
I have no idea
我不知道
I don't know where I'm going
我不知道我要去哪里
I just want to go,far away from here
我只想赶快离开这里
Just drive
你就一直往前开
As far as you can
越远越好
Sorry
对不起
It's fine.
没关系
You like MAYDAY?
你喜欢五月天
Yeah
嗯
You going to their concert next week?
那下个礼拜的演唱会你也会去看
You mean Shanghai?
上海那场
I bought the tickets
我票买了
But not going anymore
可是不去了
Why?
为什么？
I was going to propose to my girlfriend
本来想给我女朋友一个惊喜
Really big surprise for her
向他求婚
Then go to Shanghai for our honeymoon
带他去上海度蜜月
And the MAYDAY concert
顺便看五月天演唱会
But¡­
可是后来
Not any more
吹了
Sorry about that
对不起
I'm fine.
我没事
How about you?
你呢
Stop the car
停车
That's him
就是他啊
That's really him
就是他
People warned me before,but I refuse to believe
人家跟我说他会劈腿我也不信
29 minutes before,I opened the door
在29分钟之前 我打开房门
Seeing him and the other woman£¬
竟然看到他跟另一个女的
lying on my couch
躺在我买的沙发上面
Even wearing my coat
那女的身上还穿了我的外套
So it's over...
真过份…
What do you want?
你要干嘛
Sir. Sir.
先生 先生
HOSEE
HOSEE
Spit it out
别矜持啦
Fxxx Fxxx Fxxx Fxxx Fxxx
看 看 看 看 看
Louder
大声点
That's it
对 就是这样
Friggen,cheater,cheater,cheater
笨蛋 笨蛋 你劈腿 你劈腿 你劈腿
What?
怎么样
This is¡­
这…我…不是
Cheater,cheater,cheater
你劈腿 你劈腿 你劈腿
What's happen?
怎么了？
One left
还有一个
How would you do?
要让他怎么死啊
I believe in you
我相信你是真心的
When we were together
在我们在一起的过程中
I really believe in you
你都是真心的
Right now
就像现在
When you leave
你要离开
I still believe in you
我也相信你是真心的
Wishing you all the best
祝你幸福
Let's go
走拉
O.K.
好
How can you write under such conditions?
这么衰你还有办法写歌
Write what?
写个屁啦
What are you doing anyway?
不然你在干嘛
Just want to take a note
纪录一下啊
Take a note?
纪录
See how many taxis have driven by
看一下有几台空计程车不载我们了啊
How many?
几台
Feeling better?
感觉离开了吗
I'm Rene
我叫小乃
I'm Richie
我叫小齐
Wanna go somewhere?
现在去哪里
Do you still have the tickets to the concert?
你那张演唱会的票还留着吗
"I'll give you freedom"
“我给你自由”
"I'll give you alllllllll the freedom"
“我给你全部全部全部全部自由”
"This is my tenderness for giving you the freedom..."
“这是我的温柔 还给你的自由”
"I don't know"
“不知道 不明t”
"and don't want to know"
“不想要 为什么 我的心”
"My heart wants to get closer£¬"
“明明是想靠近”
"But it is still alone"
“却孤单的黎明”
"I don't know"
“不知道 不明t”
"and don't want to know"
“不想要 为什么 我的心”
"Always finds the beauty of love in loneliness£¬"
“那爱情的绮丽”
"I'll give my true love to you once and for all"
“再把我的最好的爱给你”
"Unconsciously,unwillingly£¬"
“不知不觉 不情不愿”
"Again,I return to your alley"
“又到巷子口”
"I am not crying either smiling"
“我没有哭 也没有笑”
"because it's just a dream"
“因为这是梦”
"No prerequisites,no excuses£¬ cause you said it all before"
“没有预兆 没有理由 你真的有说过”
"If there is any,I'll let you have your own"
“如果有 就让你”
"If there is any£¬ I'll let you have your own freedom"
“如果有 就让你自由”
"Freedom"
“自由”
"This is my tenderness"
“这是我的温柔”
"This is my..."
“这是我的”
"tenderness"
“温柔”
"I'll let you have your own freedom."
“就让你自由”
"How do you possess a rainbow?"
“怎么去拥有 一道彩虹”
"How do you embrace a summer wind?"
“怎么去拥抱 一夏天的风”
"The stars in the sky laugh at the people on the ground"
“天上的星星 笑地上的人”
"I can never understand why I can't feel it is enough"
“总是不能懂 不能觉得足够”
"If I fall in love with your smile"
“如果我爱上 你的笑容”
"How can I keep it,how can I possess it?"
“要怎么收藏 要怎么拥有”
"If you're happy,and it's not because of me"
“如果你快乐 不是为我”
"Would I give it up? Since that is the real possession?"
“会不会放手 其实才是拥有”
"When the wind blows by,a kite flies into the sky"
“当一阵风吹来 风筝飞上天空”
"I pray for you,and wish you all the best"
“为了你而祈祷 而祝福 而感动”
"At last,you and your shadow disappear"
“终于你身影 消失在 人海尽头”
"Then I realize,how it hurts to laugh with tears"
“才发现 笑着哭 最痛”
"That day,that hill,you and I"
“那年你和我 那个山丘”
"That kind of singing,that year's song"
“那样的唱着 那一年的歌”
"That kind of memory,all is enough"
“那样的回忆 那么足够”
"Enough that every day I can taste the loneliness"
“足够我天天 都品尝着寂寞”
"Twinkle Twinkle Little Star"
“一闪一闪亮晶晶”
"How I wonder what you are"
“满天都是小星星”
"When the wind blows by£¬ a kite flies into the sky"
“当一阵风吹来 风筝飞上天空”
"I pray for you,and wish you all the best"
“为了你而祈祷 而祝福 而感动”
"At last,you and your shadow disappear"
“终于你身影 消失在 人海尽头”
"Then I realize,how it hurts to laugh with tears"
“才发现 笑着哭 最痛”
"When the wind blows by,a kite flies into the sky"
“当一阵风吹来 风筝飞上天空”
"I pray for you,and wish you all the best"
“为了你而祈祷 而祝福 而感动”
"At last,you and your shadow disappear"
“终于你身影 消失在 人海尽头”
"Then I realize,how it hurts to laugh with tears"
“才发现 笑着哭 最痛”
"If I fall in love with your smile"
“如果我爱上 你的笑容”
"How can I keep it,how can I possess it?"
“要怎么收藏 要怎么拥有”
"If you're happy,and it's not because of me"
“如果你快乐 不是为我”
"Would I give it up? Since that is the real possession?"
“会不会放手 其实才是拥有”
"The happiness of contentment"
“知足的快乐”
"Calling me to endure my broken heart"
“叫我忍受心痛”
"Like a child depends on a shoulder"
“像孩子依赖着肩膀”
"As tears depend on a face"
“像眼泪依赖着脸庞”
"You are like an angel£¬"
“你就像天使一样”
"Giving me something to depend on£¬ giving me strength"
“给我依赖 给我力量”
"Just like a poet depends on the moonlight"
“像诗人依赖着月亮”
"As a dolphin depends on the sea"
“像海豚依赖海洋”
"You are an angel£¬"
“你是天使”
"You are my first and last heaven"
“你是我最初和最后的天堂”
"You are my angel"
“你就是我的天使”
"My guardian angel"
“保护着我的天使”
"From now on,there will be no more sadness"
“从此我再没有忧伤”
"You are my angel"
“你就是我的天使”
"The angel that brings me happiness"
“给我快乐的天使”
"Teaches me how to fly"
“甚至我学会了飞翔”
"Flying through the impermanence of the human world"
“飞过人间的无常”
"Understanding love is a precious storehouse"
“才懂爱才是宝藏”
"No matter what the world becomes"
“不管世界变得怎么样”
"Having you is my only heaven"
“只要有你就会是天堂”
"Like a child depends on a shoulder"
“像孩子依赖着肩膀”
"As tears depend on a face"
“像眼泪依赖着脸庞”
"You are like an angel"
“你就像天使一样”
"Giving me something to depend on£¬ giving me strength"
“给我依赖 给我力量”
"Just like a poet depends on the moonlight"
“像诗人依赖着月亮”
"As a dolphin depends on the sea"
“像海豚依赖海洋”
"You are an angel"
“你是天使”
"You are my first and last heaven"
“你是我最初和最后的天堂”
"You are my angel"
“你就是我的天使”
"My guardian angel"
“保护着我的天使”
"From now on,there will be no more sadness"
“从此我再没有忧伤”
"You are my angel"
“你就是我的天使”
"The angel that brings me happiness"
“给我快乐的天使”
"Teaches me how to fly"
“甚至我学会了飞翔”
"Flying through the impermanence of the human world"
“飞过人间的无常”
"Understanding love is a precious storehouse"
“才懂爱才是宝藏”
"No matter what the world becomes"
“不管世界变得怎么样”
"Having you is my only heaven"
“只要有你就会是天堂”
"Like a child depends on a shoulder"
“像孩子依赖着肩膀”
"As tears depend on a face"
“像眼泪依赖着脸庞”
"You are like an angel"
“你就像天使一样”
"Giving me something to depend on£¬ giving me strength"
“给我依赖 给我力量”
"Just like a poet depends on the moonlight"
“像诗人依赖着月亮”
"As a dolphin depends on the sea"
“像海豚依赖海洋”
"You are an angel"
“你是天使”
"You are my first and last heaven"
“你是我最初和最后的天堂”
"My last heaven"
“最后的天堂”
Good morning everyone!
早上好 听众朋友驾驶员朋友
Welcome to "Morning Shanghai"!
欢迎大家收听早安上海节目
Today is Tuesday
今天是星期二
We had a lovely Monday yesterday
昨天本市天气挺好阳光充沛
With the highest temperature for 20.8 degrees Celsius
最高的气温升到了20.8度
However,it will be cooler this morning£¬ around 10 degrees Celsius
预计今天早晨最低气温降到10度左右
Greeen
青青
Why so slow?
怎么那么慢啊？
Another point
又得一分
Hey,deliver boy
雨剑
Take this please
来来来这快递快帮忙送
Hurry up
赶紧啊
- O.K. - Be careful
好       路上骑车小心
O.K.
好
I'm back
哥回来
I'm off
哥出门
Delivery for Mr. Lee
李文伍先生快递
Wait a sec
你等一下
Oh,great,it finally arrived
来啦来啦 终于来啦来啦
- Thanks - O.K.
好 谢谢       谢啦谢啦
No. 357,JhaoHua Rd.
昭化路357号
The tall guy£¬
个子高高的
with beard who loves money
留胡子 很爱钱的那个
O.K.,no problem
OK 没问题
O.K.
好 加油
I am back
哥回来
Good morning everyone!
早安上海 天天精彩
Let's all have a goooood "Morning Shanghai"
让好心情从早安上海启航
I have a delivery for Mr. Jin-Hang Shi
不好意思 石锦航快递
No,it's for Mr. Shi Jin-Hang,not Stone
不对 是石锦航 不是石头
I am Mr. Shi,and I am Stone
石锦航就是我啊 我就是石头啊
This is for Mr. Shi
这是给石锦航的
Yes,I am Mr. Shi
是啊 我就是石锦航啊
And I am Stone
我也是石头啊
You are the Stone from MAYDAY?
你是五月天的石头
Yes,I am
是啊
Excuse me
不好意思
Can you sign my arm?
能麻烦你再在我手上再签一个名吗
Of course!
可以啊
Thank you,thank you
谢谢 谢谢
Bye
Bye
Excuse me
不好意思
Can I have...
另外四个
The other four's autographs as well?
可以再帮我签一下吗
Yu-Jian
雨剑
Your salary for today
今天的工资
Thanks
好 谢谢
Hi,I need a ticket for the MAYDAY concert
你好 我要一张五月天的票
The $355 one
355的
O.K.
好 好
Last one,lucky boy
最后一张啦 算你好运
See£¬
你看
This is what a brother's for I keep my promise
哥答应你的事情没忘记吧
Let's go
走
To your favorite,MAYDAY concert
带你去看你最喜欢的 五月天演唱会
Sir.
师父
We're in Shanghai already
我们已经到上海了
I'll take good care of her
对 我会好好照顾乐乐的
No worries
没事
Thief,thief!
小偷 小偷
Get lost
让开
Stop!
别跑
You! Stop!
小偷别跑
Bro.,here you go
大哥 包给你了 包给你了
Please stop,please stop
大哥别打 大哥别打
Get off!
滚
The concert will start in 30 minutes
演唱会再三十分钟后就要开始
Please get in line
请往前排队
Now please get in line
请现在开始依序排队
Watch your step,don't push
注意你的安全 不要拥挤
Move forward
往前面移动
Take your ticket with you
把你的票拿在手上
Mind your step,watch out,please be aware
请不要拥挤 注意安全
Don't be so sad
你别伤心了
Lele,don't worry so much
乐乐 不要伤心了
Dad spent tons of efforts sending me here
爸爸好不容易让我来的
Lele,don't be so sad
乐乐你别伤心了
Don't be so unhappy
不要难过了 乐乐
See,your bag
你看 包包
Thanks
谢谢
What's up,Lele?
怎么了 乐乐
What?
什么事
Don't cry. What's up?
别哭了 怎么了
I lost my wallet,and the ticket is in there
我的皮夹子不见了 演唱会票在里面
Try to find again,are you absolutely sure?
你再仔细找找 你确定票在皮夹里吗
- They are really gone - Try again
真的不见了       再仔细找找
None
不在
Again¡­
你再找找
When I am well enough
哥 等我病好了
Can you take me to the MAYDAY concert?
你带我去看五月天的演唱会 好不好
I will take you wherever you like to go
哥哥一定带你去看
It is a deal
一言为定
No worries,you guys go
没事 你去看吧
Use mine
用我的去吧
I just remember that I have something important
哥哥突然想到有事情去不了了
Remember to scream when you see MAYDAY for me
记得看到五月天要帮哥哥大声喊加油
Thanks
谢谢
Now,go
去吧
"Suppose that this world and I are different"
“当 我和世界不一样”
"That will make us different as well"
“那就让我不一样”
"To me,holding fast means once unyielding"
“坚持对我来说”
"Ever more unyielding"
“就是以刚克刚”
"If I were to compromise my principles"
“我 如果对自己妥协”
"Or lie to myself"
“如果对自己说谎”
"Others might forgive me"
“即使别人原谅”
"But I'd never forgive myself"
“我也不能原谅”
"The most perfect wish"
“最美的愿望”
"Has got to be the craziest"
“一定最疯狂”
"I am my own God"
“我就是我自己的神”
"At the place where I live"
“在我活的地方”
"Me and my last bit of stubbornness"
“我和我最后的倔强”
"Grasping tightly in my two hands£¬ absolutely not letting go"
“握紧双手绝对不放”
"The next stop may be paradise"
“下一站是不是天堂”
"Disappointments can't destroy hope"
“就算失望不能绝望”
"Me and my proud stubbornness"
“我和我骄傲的倔强”
"I sing loudly in the wind"
“我在风中大声的唱”
"This time,I'm crazy for my own sake£¬"
“这一次为自己疯狂”
"Just this time£¬ me and my last bit of stubbornness"
“就这一次 我和我的倔强”
"People who love me need not to be nervous"
“对 爱我的人别紧张”
"My obstinacy is good and honest"
“我的固执很善良”
"The dirtier my hands become"
“我的手越肮脏”
"The clearer I can see"
“眼神越是发光”
"You don't mind my past mistakes"
“你 不在乎我的过往”
"Because you can see my wings"
“看到了我的翅膀”
"And you remind me that only after being burned in the fire"
“你说被火烧过”
"Can a phoenix be reborn"
“才能出现凤凰”
"Traveling against the wind"
“逆风的方向”
"Is the best way to fly"
“更适合飞翔”
"Countless people throwing obstacles at my way"
“我不怕千万人阻挡”
"However,I only fear my own surrender"
“只怕自己投降”
"Me and my last bit of stubbornness"
“我和我最后的倔强”
"Grasping tightly in my two hands£¬ absolutely not letting go"
“握紧双手绝对不放”
"The next stop may be paradise"
“下一站是不是天堂”
"Disappointments can't destroy hope"
“就算失望不能绝望”
"Me and my proud stubbornness"
“我和我骄傲的倔强”
"I sing loudly in the wind"
“我在风中大声的唱”
"This time,I'm crazy for my own sake£¬"
“这一次为自己疯狂”
"Just this time£¬ me and my last bit of stubbornness"
“就这一次 我和我的倔强”
"Me and my last bit of stubbornness"
“我和我最后的倔强”
"Grasping tightly in my two hands£¬ absolutely not letting go"
“握紧双手绝对不放”
"The next stop may be paradise"
“下一站是不是天堂”
"Disappointments can't destroy hope"
“就算失望不能绝望”
"Me and my proud stubbornness"
“我和我骄傲的倔强”
"I sing loudly in the wind"
“我在风中大声的唱”
"This time,I'm crazy for my own sake£¬"
“这一次为自己疯狂”
"Just this time£¬ me and my last bit of stubbornness"
“就这一次 我和我的倔强”
"Just this time,let me sing it out loud"
“就这一次 让我大声唱”
"Granted that disappointments can't destroy hope"
“就算失望 不能绝望”
"Just this time,just me and my¡­"
“就这一次 我和我的”
"Just this time£¬ me and my stubbornness"
“就这一次 我和我的倔强”
"I believe in bitter tears"
“我相信 苦涩的眼泪”
"I don't believe in sweet words"
“我不信 甜美的誓言”
"I believe in music"
“我相信 音乐就该音乐”
"I believe in pure love"
“我相信 爱情的纯粹”
"I don't believe in poems with flowery diction"
“我不信 华丽的诗篇”
"I believe in lively debates"
“我相信 热烈的争辨”
"I don't believe in silent harmony"
“我不信 无声的和谐”
"I believe in seconds and moments"
“我相信 秒秒的瞬间”
"I don't believe in forever and ever"
“我不信 年年的永远”
"I believe in rock 'n' roll"
“我相信 摇滚就能万岁”
"Open your mouth OA OA"
“快张开你的嘴 OA OA”
"Don't care who you are OA OA"
“再不管你是谁 OA OA”
"Life is too short"
“人生都太短暂”
"Don't think,don't be afraid,don't retreat"
“别想 别怕 别后退”
"Now is the moment"
“现在 就是 永远”
"The year I was born OA OA"
“出生的那一年 OA OA”
"And now I am here OA OA"
“转眼就这一天 OA OA”
"Life is too short"
“人生都太短暂”
"Go crazy,go love,and go waste"
“去疯 去爱 去浪费”
"Singing again with me OA OA OA"
“和我 再唱 OA OA OA”
"I believe in seconds and moments"
“我相信 秒秒的瞬间”
"I don't believe in forever and ever"
“我不信 年年的永远”
"I believe in rock 'n' roll"
“我相信 摇滚就能万岁”
"Open your mouth OA OA"
“快张开你的嘴 OA OA”
"Don't care who you are OA OA"
“再不管你是谁 OA OA”
"Life is too short"
“人生都太短暂”
"Don't think,don't be afraid,don't retreat"
“别想 别怕 别后退”
"Now is the moment"
“现在 就是 永远”
"The year I was born OA OA"
“出生的那一年 OA OA”
"And now I am here OA OA"
“转眼就这一天 OA OA”
"Life is too short"
“人生都太短暂”
"Go crazy,go love,and go waste"
“去疯 去爱 去浪费”
"Sing with me again OA OA OA"
“和我再唱 OA OA OA”
"O-A O-A"
“O-A O-A”